### Yan Long

2260 Hayward Street, Ann Arbor, MI, 48105

yanlong@umich.edu ♦ https://yanlong.site/ ♦ (734) 881-5577

### RESEARCH SUMMARY

My research aims to protect the security and privacy of sensing-based information and embedded systems, with an emphasis on the software-hardware interfaces. My research has applications to securing emerging technology in cyber-physical systems, wearable and medical devices, and the greater frontier of ubiquitous computing. I work towards the next generation of sensing systems that have science-based security and privacy protections as a fundamental building block.

#### **EDUCATION**

### University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI

Sep 2019 - Present

- · Ph.D. in Electrical and Computer Engineering
- Thesis: Modeling and Mitigating Side Channels in Optical & Embedded Sensing Systems
- Dissertation committee: Kevin Fu (chair), Mingyan Liu (co-chair), Alanson Sample, Pei Zhang, Jean-Baptiste Jeannin

### Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China

Sep 2015 - June 2019

- B.Eng in Electronic and Information Engineering
- Thesis: Sound Field-based Liveness Detection in Voice Authentication
- Advisors: Wenyuan Xu, Xiaoyu Ji

### WORK EXPERIENCE

University of Michigan, Ann Arbor, MI Lead Graduate Research Assistant, Security and Privacy Research Group	Sep 2019 - Present
Zhejiang University, Hangzhou, China Undergraduate Research Assistant, Ubiquitous System Security Lab	Sep 2017 - June 2019
<b>UCLA</b> , Los Angeles, CA Summer Visiting Researcher, Biomimetic Research Lab	July 2018 - Sep 2018
<b>Thundercomm</b> , Chongqing, China Embedded Development Intern	June 2017 - Sep 2017

#### **AWARDS & HONORS**

Rackham Predoctoral Fellowship (top 6 PhD candidates of UM ECE&CS)	2023
NSF/NSPW Student Travel Support Grant	2022
ACM SIGMOBILE Research Highlight on GetMobile	2022
SenSys Best Poster Runner-up Award (top 8%)	2020
Outstanding Undergraduate Thesis of Zhejiang University	2019
UCLA Cross-disciplinary Scholarship in Science and Technology	2018
Zhejiang Provincial Government Scholarship (top 3% of school)	2018
Samsung Scholarship (top 5% of school)	2018
Zhejiang University Outstanding Volunteer Service Award	2017

Last updated: July 2023

\* denotes equal contribution

### **Refereed Conference & Workshop Publications**

# C9 GhostType: The Limits of Using Contactless Electromagnetic Interference to Inject Phantom Keys into Analog Circuits of Keyboards

Qinhong Jiang, Yanze Ren, <u>Yan Long</u>, Chen Yan, Yumai Sun, Xiaoyu Ji, Kevin Fu, Wenyuan Xu Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (**NDSS**) 2024

# C8 Characterizing and Mitigating Touchtone Eavesdropping in Smartphone Motion Sensors Connor Bolton\*, Yan Long\*, Jun Han, Josiah Hester, Kevin Fu 26th International Symposium on Research in Attacks, Intrusions, and Defenses (RAID) 2023 [acceptance rate = 50/213 = 23.5%]

# C7 Side Eye: Characterizing the Limits of POV Acoustic Eavesdropping from Smartphone Cameras with Rolling Shutters and Movable Lenses

Yan Long, Pirouz Naghavi, Blas Kojusner, Kevin Butler, Sara Rampazzi, Kevin Fu 44th Annual IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P) 2023 [acceptance rate = 195/1147 = 17%]

# C6 Private Eye: On the Limits of Textual Screen Peeking via Eyeglass Reflections in Video Conferencing

Yan Long, Chen Yan, Shilin Xiao, Shivan Prasad, Wenyuan Xu, Kevin Fu 44th Annual IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (IEEE S&P) 2023 [acceptance rate = 195/1147 = 17%]

# C5 Position Paper: Space System Threat Models Must Account for Satellite Sensor Spoofing

Benjamin Cyr, Yan Long, Takeshi Sugawara, Kevin Fu
Workshop on Security of Space and Satellite Systems (SpaceSec) 2023

### C4 Side Auth: Sensor Side Channels Considered Beneficial by Synthesizing Virtual Sensors for Authentication

Yan Long, Kevin Fu

ACM/ACSA New Security Paradigms Workshop (NSPW) 2022

[acceptance rate = 38%]

# C3 VeriMask: Facilitating Decontamination of N95 Masks in the COVID-19 Pandemic: Challenges, Lessons Learned, and Safeguarding the Future

Yan Long, Alexander Curtiss, Sara Rampazzi, Josiah Hester, Kevin Fu ACM International Joint Conference on Pervasive and Ubiquitous Computing (UbiComp/IMWUT) 2021

[acceptance rate = 22%, impact factor = 4.96]

### C2 The Catcher in the Field: A Fieldprint based Spoofing Detection for Text-Independent Speaker Verification

Chen Yan\*, Yan Long\*, Xiaoyu Ji, Wenyuan Xu 26th ACM Conference on Computer and Communications Security (ACM CCS) 2019 [acceptance rate = 149/934 = 16%]

#### C1 A Novel Biomimetic Stimulator System for Neural Implant

Wang, Po-Min, Stanislav Culaclii, William Yang, Yan Long, Jonathan Massachi, Yi-Kai Lo, Wentai Liu

9th International IEEE/EMBS Conference on Neural Engineering (IEEE/EMBS NER) 2019

### **Refereed Journal & Magazine Publications**

J2 VeriMask: Sensor Platform for Decontamination of N95 Masks

Yan Long, Alexander Curtiss, Sara Rampazzi, Josiah Hester, Kevin Fu GetMobile: Mobile Computing and Communications. June 2022, Vol. 26 Iss. 2. pp 25-28

J1 Protecting COVID-19 Vaccine Transportation and Storage from Analog Cybersecurity
Threats

Yan Long, Sara Rampazzi, Takeshi Sugawara, Kevin Fu Biomedical Instrumentation & Technology (BI&T) 55, no. 3, Oct 2021

#### **Posters & Demos**

P2 Limiting the Optical-Electromagnetic Side Channel Leakage of Smartphone Cameras
Yan Long, Kevin Fu

NSF CHEST Meeting 2023

P1 Automating Decontamination of N95 Masks for Frontline Workers in COVID-19 Pandemic Yan Long, Alexander Curtiss, Sara Rampazzi, Josiah Hester, Kevin Fu

18th ACM Conference on Embedded Networked Sensor Systems (SenSys) 2020

[Best Poster Award Runner Up – COVID-19 Response Research (Top 8%)]

#### Submissions in Review

S2 EM Eye: Characterizing Electromagnetic Side-channel Eavesdropping on Embedded Cameras

Yan Long\*, Qinhong Jiang\*, Chen Yan, Tobias Alam, Xiaoyu Ji, Wenyuan Xu, Kevin Fu Network and Distributed System Security Symposium (NDSS) 2024

S1 SampleGuard: Sampling-based Runtime Detection of Android Zero-permission Sensor Usage from User Space

Yan Long, Tobias Alam, Kevin Fu

Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC) 2023

### **PATENTS**

#### **Speaker Detection from Muted Terrorist Propaganda Videos**

US Patent, disclosed, 2023

#### A Method for Detecting Voice Replay Attacks

Xioayu Ji, <u>Yan Long</u>, Wenyuan Xu, Chen Yan *China Invention Patent, ZL 2019 1 0303649.3* 

#### TEACHING EXPERIENCE

EECS 498/598 Special Topics in Embedded Security (Undergraduate + Graduate)	Fall 2022
EECS 505 Computational Data Science & Machine Learning (Graduate)	Fall 2021
EECS 298 Applied Computational ML for Scientists and Engineers (Undergraduate)	Fall 2021
EECS 501 Probability & Random Process (Graduate)	Winter 2021

Last updated: July 2023 3/4

### **SERVICE**

### **Professional Activities**

Technical program committee: IEEE MSN 2023

Organizer and panelist: Annual Embedded Security Workshop 2020

Reviewer: IEEE TIFS, IEEE IoT-J, ACM TOPS, ACM IMWUT

Sub-reviewer: IEEE TIE, ACM MobiCom, USENIX Security, ACM CCS

### **Student Advising**

Emiko Sano	High-school student	2023-Present
Tobias Alam	B.S. Computer Science (two papers under review)	2022-Present
Yumai Sun	M.S. Electrical and Computer Engineering (paper at NDSS'24)	2022-2023
Haoliang Cheng	B.S. Computer Engineering (next: ECE master's at CMU)	2022-2023
Shivan Prasad	B.S. Computer Science (paper at SP'23)	2021-2022
Mia Li	B.S. Computer Science (now: Salesforce)	2020
Weikun Lyu	B.S. Computer Science (now: Meta)	2020

### Volunteering

Vice president of Zhejiang University Alumni Association of Michigan	2023-Present
Vice president of Red Cross student center of Zhejiang University	2015-2017